lib.oh.us 2016-03-20

# OPLIN Privacy Policy | OPLIN

#### Ohio Public Library Information Network (OPLIN) Web Site Privacy Policy

Issued March 28, 2000  
Approved by the OPLIN Board of Trustees June 9, 2000

Thank you for visiting the Ohio Public Library Information Network (OPLIN) Web site and for reviewing OPLIN's privacy policy.

The most important thing for you to know is that OPLIN collects **no** personal information about you when you visit the OPLIN Web site unless you _choose_ to provide that information.

You do not have to give OPLIN any personal information to visit its Web site. OPLIN does not track or permanently record information about individuals and their visits.

Here is how OPLIN handles information about your visit to its Web site.

####   
Information Collected and Stored Automatically

If all you do is look around the Web site, read text, or download information, OPLIN will gather and store certain information about your visit automatically.

This information does not identify you personally.

OPLIN automatically collects and stores only the following information about your visit:

  1. The Internet domain (for example, "earthlink.net" if you use a private Internet access account such as EarthLink or "yourschool.edu" if you connect from a university's domain) and IP address (a number automatically assigned to your computer whenever you surf the Web) from which you access the OPLIN Web site
  2. The type of browser and operating system you use
  3. The date and time you visit
  4. The topics you view
  5. If you linked to the OPLIN Web site from another Web site, the address of that Web site
  6. If you search the OPLIN Web site, the search words or phrases you use and the results of the search

####   
How OPLIN Uses This Information

OPLIN uses this information to help make its site more functional for visitors -- to learn about the number of visitors to its site and the kinds of information they seek.

Browser and operating information allow the OPLIN Web site to take you to the version of site that best conforms to the capabilities of your tools. Visitors using text-only browsers or older versions of graphical browsers go automatically to the OPLIN text-only site.

Search results disclose whether the OPLIN Web site contains the kinds of information its visitors seek and are used for planning future additions to the site. These results are not linked to domain, IP, or browser data.

The OPLIN Web site uses Web "cookies" only when necessary to complete a transaction, and then only temporarily. OPLIN does not use persistent cookies.

####   
If You Send Personal Information to OPLIN

If you choose to provide us with personal information -- sending an e-mail to the OPLIN Director or other OPLIN staff members, or using the online contact form -- OPLIN uses that information only to respond to your message and to help get you the information you have requested.

OPLIN only shares the information you give it with other agencies or individuals who may be able to respond to your inquiry or as otherwise required by law. OPLIN does not create individual profiles with the information you provide, nor does it give that information to any private organizations. OPLIN does not collect information for commercial marketing.

####   
All Information Subject to Open Record Laws

Information collected automatically on the OPLIN Web site, as well as e-mail sent to OPLIN, is generally subject to state open record laws except as provided by Ohio or federal law.

####   
Receiving Information from OPLIN

Visitors to the Web site receive information from OPLIN only in response to their own requests.

####   
Links to Other Sites

The OPLIN Web site has links to many other governmental, commercial, educational, and individual Web sites. Once you follow a link from the OPLIN Web site to another site, you are subject to that new site's privacy policy rather than to OPLIN's privacy policy.

OPLIN does not supervise or control public-access workstations. Be aware that if you send personal information of any kind to any Web site from a public-access workstation, that information very well may remain in the cached files of that workstation and, therefore, open to discovery by other users.

####   
Contact

If you want more information about OPLIN's privacy policy, contact:

Executive Director  
Ohio Public Library Information Network  
2323 W. Fifth Ave, Suite 130  
Columbus, OH 43204  
Phone: (614) 728-5252  
E-mail: [director@oplin.org](mailto:director@oplin.org)
